RODERICK FLOWERS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | MILITARY VETERAN

roderickflowersjr@gmail.com \((470)\) 301-0390 \(\mathbf{Q}\) Riverdale, GA in roderick-flowers-3a921821b/\(\mathbf{Q}\) rfdoom

SUMMARY

United States Air Force Veteran and Software Engineer with an expertise in Avionics, Data Analytics and Reporting. Managed 20+ mechanics in repairing aircraft valued over \$1bn and captured flight data for over 300 missions responsible for the in-flight refueling of military aircraft. Utilizing these prior experiences in the world of technology to produce user-friendly platforms that create return customers.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, Django REST Framework, React.js

PROJECTS

URL Shortener/Expander

Incorporated multiple API calls using Django REST Framework and Python Uses PostgreSQL to store URLs with a custom nickname, allowing a user to immediately receive the long and short URL

EXPERIENCE

United States Air Force

Avionics Technician, McConnell Air Force Base

Mar. 2016 - July 2021

- *Conducted troubleshooting of 50+ aircraft communication and navigation equipment components.
- *Performed the safety evaluation of aircraft to ensure flight reliability 7 crew members per flight.
- *Led 20+ teams of technicians through problem-solving and proper techniques for multiple >\$1bn aircraft.

Flight Records Manager, McConnell Air Force Base

July 2021 - Mar. 2022

- *Maintained records of the flight mission, outcomes, and areas for improvement of over 30 aircraft.
- *Responsible for the efficient scheduling of maintenance actions per aircraft.
- *Managed teams of 14 personnel in attaining a record low error percentage of 13%.

EDUCATION

Southern New Hampshire University Code Platoon

May 2021 - Current

Jan. 2022 - May 2022